Isaak Krautwurst

Q Chicago, IL
 ■ hello@idkraut.dev
 ★ idkraut.dev

Profile

Software engineer with experience in Ruby, JavaScript, Go, and a variety of frameworks and cloud technologies. I'm passionate about learning, creative thinking, and collaborative development. I am the co-creator of Hypha, an open-source observability framework for distributed systems.

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, *Hypha* ☑

2021 – present

- Designed, prototyped, and built Hypha: an automated, end-to-end telemetry pipeline that sets up distributed tracing, aggregates existing logs, and correlates logs with traces.
- Engineered the automated instrumentation of Node.js applications to emit logs and traces using OpenTelemetry SDK and Collector.
- Implemented the containerization and configuration of backend services including OpenTelemetry Gateway Collector, Jaeger, Grafana Loki, and Grafana using Docker Compose.
- Developed a custom UI powered by Grafana, providing an intuitive and focused debugging interface.
- Implemented the scaling of Loki and Jaeger services with read/write/store multi-service deployments using Nginx as a reverse proxy for service discovery.
- Engineered the automated provisioning and teardown of AWS cloud infrastructure via AWS CLI, ECS Fargate, and Docker Compose ECS integration.
- Collaborated closely with a remote team of 4 engineers, including daily standups and pair programming.
- Authored Hypha's technical case study □

Software Engineer, *Self-Employed*

2020 - 2021

- Rekwest Bin A tool for receiving and debugging webhooks (Go, Nginx, Digital Ocean Droplet, MongoDB, PM2)
- Reaction A trello-inspired Kanban board for project management (React, Redux, Express, MongoDB, Node.js)

Tutor, Academic Approach

2016 - 2021

- Worked closely with hundreds of students to improve problem-solving skills and academic knowledge
- Designed and taught curricula for grades 6-12, customized for individual learning styles and needs

Skills

Languages

Ruby, JavaScript, Go, SQL, HTML, CSS

Frameworks

Express, React, Redux, Sinatra, ¡Query, Handlebars

Cloud

DigitalOcean, Heroku, AWS (EC2, IAM, ECS, ECR, Fargate, EFS)

Other Technologies

Docker, PostgreSQL, Node.js, MongoDB, HTTP, REST APIs, WebSocket, Webhooks, SSH, Git/GitHub

Education

Software Engineering & Web Development, Launch School □

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum, with progression gated by written exams and live coding interviews to develop problem solving and technical skills.